Mss.B.K132a
American Philosophical Society
Kane logbooks, 1844-1857
Mss.B.K132a
American Philosophical Society
12.0 Volume(s)
12 volumes.
Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857
Various authors
Volume 1-12
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Presented by Dr. Oliver Cope, 1967.
Naval History Note
Important source material in antebellum American naval history.
Early American History Note
These eleven volumes contain Elisha Kent Kane’s logbooks for voyages he took from 1844-1857. MOLE contains a detailed index of them.
Americans Abroad; International Trade.; International Travel; Miscellaneous; Travel Narratives and Journals
- 1. Log of the ship Edward O'Brien, 1853-1856. 1 vol., 1; 1.0 Volume(s); Kaspar, Peter (Volume 1)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition note
  Presented by Dr. Oliver Cope, 1967
- 2. Log of the schooner Leesburg, 1850-1853., 2; 1.0 Volume(s); Boon, W. B. (Volume 1)
  Presented by Dr. Oliver Cope, 1967.
- 3. Log of the brig New World, 1852., 3; 2.0 Volume(s); Caster, A. (Volume 2)
- 4. Log of the ship Wings of the Morning, 1854-1855., 4; 1.0 Volume(s) (Volume 1)
- 5. Log of the ship Savanah, 1852-1853., 5; 1.0 Volume(s); Ducan, R. R. (Volume 1)
- 6. Log of the ship Sandusky, 1853-1854., 6; 1.0 Volume(s); Rice, J. D. (Volume 1)
- 7. Log of the U.S. Frigate Brandywine, 1843-1845., 7; 1.0 Volume(s); Parker, F. A. (Volume 1)
- 8. Journal of the U. S. Sloop of War Albany, 1846-1847., 8; 1.0 Volume(s); Breese, Samuel L., (Samuel Livingston), 1794-1870 (Volume 1)
- 9. Log of the U. S. Frigate Cumberland, 1844-1845., 9; 1.0 Volume(s); Breese, Samuel L., (Samuel Livingston), 1794-1870 (Volume 1)
- 10. Log of the bark Roderic, 1853., 10; 1.0 Volume(s); Smith, Robert (Volume 1)
- 11. Log of the schooner Telegraph, 1856-1857. 1 vol., 11; 1.0 Volume(s); Roath, H. G. (Volume 1)